# Rama Dhonanto

Co-founder at Sportdeca.com

ramapost2000@yahoo.com

## Summary

Rama is the go to go person when it comes to startup, digital, eCommerce, and entrepreneurship. He co-founded Sportdeca, which has become one of the largest sport eCommerce in Indonesia. He's also the Head of Digital Marketing at Shopdeca, the sister company of Sportdeca. On December 2015, Shopdeca and Sportdeca were acquired by Migme Global. Since then, along with Head of Global eCommerce, he manages the whole eCommerce division of Migme. That includes Sold Malaysia, Sold Singapore, Sold Indonesia, Shopdeca, Sportdeca, and Migshop.

As a person who has the entrepreneurial spirit, Rama has involved in different part of the business. Some of them include:

- Head of Service at Sportdeca, Shopdeca, and Sold Indonesia
- Technology Lead at Migme eCommerce Global
- Head of Marketing at Migme eCommerce Global

Prior to that, Rama was working at 3 biggest Telco companies in New Zealand. He was working directly to consumers, businesses, and service providers to assist new technologies such as broadband, ISDN, WCDMA network and fibre optic

One of his mission is to build products that matters to many people. Rama is also active at GEPI (Global Entrepreneur Program Indonesia) community, he has spoken and done few mentoring sessions either with universities, young entrepreneurs, or to his peers in retail and eCommerce market. You can see the details under volunteer session.

Rama has a degree of Information Technology from Wollongong University and Information System Science from Massey University. On his leisure time, he loves doing sport, music, travelling, and volunteering for under served kids.

# Experience

## Technology Lead at Migme eCommerce at migme

December 2015 - Present (8 months)

Migme eCommerce consists of Shopdeca, Sportdeca and Sold.id in Indonesia, Sold.my in Malaysia, Sold.sg in Singapore and Migshop in Indonesia and India. Since the acquisition of Shopdeca by Migme December 2015, Rama has led few technology projects include:

- Implementation of Warehouse Management System for Sold Malaysia
- Implementation of new eCommerce platform for Sold Malaysia and Indonesia
- Integration of new EDM system for Sold Malaysia and Indonesia

## Digital Marketing Lead at Shopdeca.com

December 2015 - Present (8 months)

Launched in July 2013 out of Jakarta with an entrepreneurial spirit and a passionate vision of bringing design to the people. Composed of an assortment of quality and unique design products from South East Asian and International designers and brands.

Ranging from women's and men's apparel, footwear, accessories, jewellery, home living, tech gadgets, novelties and travel companions with an upcoming kids collection.

Responsible to all marketing activities include:

- Digital Marketing
- Social Media
- Partnership

#### Co-founder, Head of Operations & Marketing at Sportdeca

October 2014 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Sportdeca is an online store that focuses on active lifestyle products. Our aim is to be the ultimate online destination for sport in Indonesia. We differentiate ourselves by providing excellent service, high customer engagement and comprehensive culture. We're proud that as of now, Sportdeca has become the biggest sport E-commerce in Indonesia.

In December 2015, Sportdeca and its sister company Shopdeca were acquired by Migme and joined a bigger family.

My role is to manage the whole operation in the business which includes:

- Merchandising Strategy
- Production Process
- Business Strategy
- Marketing Plan

- Customer Service
- Logistic and Supply Chain
- IT & Web Development

#### Co Owner at Wiloka

May 2014 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Wiloka is a property development business which focuses on building comfortable, safe, and affordable houses.

What's special about us is the option not just to own a house but also become great investors. Buying a house with us means that you're putting yourself in a great investment with a certain return. We do a buy back option after one year of you ownership with a significant return of investment.

At the moment, we are building Griya Wiloka in Jatikramat, Pondok Gede, Bekasi. There are 19 houses in the area/ Type 42, 45 and 102. Please see www.wiloka.com/griyawiloka

#### Founder & CEO at Ovenue

March 2014 - October 2014 (8 months)

Ovenue is an online marketplace for venue rentals that connects users with property to rent with users looking to rent the space. Tell us what you need on your event, submit the online form and receive multiple offers from hundreds of venues in less than 24 hours.

# Host for Get in The Ring Indonesia 2014 at Global Entrepreneurship Program Indonesia

September 2014 - September 2014 (1 month)

Get in the Ring is a worldwide podium for startups to raise capital. It was initiated by the Erasmus Centre for Entrepreneurship in 2009 to bring the most promising entrepreneurs from around the world in contact with investors, customers, and potential partners. In addition to connecting startups, Get in the Ring inspires the next generation to start their own entrepreneurial journey.

Get in the Ring: The Investment Battle is a worldwide competition for the most promising startups to secure their investment of up to €1,000,000. The competition is a featured event of the Global Entrepreneurship Week. Through 8 Regional Finals 8 startups will be selected for the International Final which will take place on the 21st of November, 2014, in Rotterdam, the Netherlands.

#### CMO at Dinoiki

2014 - 2014 (less than a year)

Started in 2009 as a freelancer, now we start as a company in August 2014. We've been focused on developing digital products and services that people use. Our type of work mostly developing website solutions, but now we also penetrated to mobile app solutions too.

Dinoiki is a digital solutions company that focused on developing top quality, robustness and customer oriented solutions. It is important to us to make a product your customer will use and a product that you love to have. We provide digital solutions that based on web, android and iOS platform

## Technical Analyst at Chorus

December 2011 - August 2013 (1 year 9 months)

- Second level support of access network incidents
- Investigated, analyzed, and resolved incidents within SLA
- Updated customer customers within agreed timeframes in service management system
- Management of incidents escalated to 3rd party vendors and process partners
- Proactively monitored customer issues for resolution
- Provided assistance to Senior Technical Specialist by investigating root cause diagnosis
- Created and updated customer and process documentation (e.g. Standard Operating Procedures)
- Services supported: voice lines (PSTN), complex voice (ISDN and Centrex), layer 1 & 2 bit-stream access (ADSL and VDSL) and High Speed Network Service (HSNS)

#### Technical Support at Vodafone New Zealand

October 2009 - December 2011 (2 years 3 months)

Responsible products: residential & business lines, ADSL, VoIP, domain, and hosting

#### Faults Representative at Telecom New Zealand

January 2008 - August 2009 (1 year 8 months)

Responsible products: Voice lines, ISDN, CDMA/WCDMA network, mobile broadband, smart phones, and wireless data card

#### One on one Sales Person at Farmers Trading Company Ltd

June 2006 - January 2008 (1 year 8 months)

#### **Publications**

#### Apa Yang Saya Pelajari di Acara Endeavor Indonesia Untuk Membangun Suatu Bisnis

Startupbisnis March 12, 2014

Authors: Rama Dhonanto

My summary of a Startup event "Scale up 101" organized by Endeavor Indonesia

# Memulai Bisnis Online : 4 Hal Utama yang Harus diperhatikan ketika Membuat B2C eCommerce oleh @ramadhonanto

Startupbisnis.com March 19, 2015

Authors: Rama Dhonanto

Few things I learned from building Sportdeca.com

#### Honors and Awards

## **Spotlight Award**

Chorus

March 2012

Spotlight is a recognition award for those who have done an outstanding contribution to the company. My contribution was handling Chorus power outage on 8th of March which caused our operational systems shut down for several hours.

#### Courses

#### **Technical Analyst**

Chorus
Time Management Training
Negotiation Skill
Business Writing Skill
Persuading & Influencing Course

#### **Technical Support**

Vodafone New Zealand Toastmasters

# Volunteer Experience

#### Master Ceremony of ASEAN Festival at Society for Southeast Asian Communities

November 2012 - Present

A cultural event representing the member countries of ASEAN brought by ASEAN embassies, Society for Southeast Asian Communities (SSEAC), and New Zealand Maori Tourism Council.

#### Keynote Speaker - Accelerating the Power of eCommerce at Escom Events

June 2016 - Present

retail.escom-events.com

#### Voluntary Team Leader at New Zealand Red Cross

May 2013 - Present

Leading a team of volunteers to raise some funds during Red Cross appeal week

#### Master Ceremony of Indonesian Fair 2012 at Indonesian Embassy in New Zealand

October 2012 - Present

An event to promote Indonesia's tourism and culture to New Zealand

#### Volunteer Support Worker at Refugee Services at New Zealand Red Cross

March 2013 - Present

Voluntary position for a 6 month placement working in a team of volunteers to provide resettlement support for a newly arrived refugees.

## Mentor at Origin Business Club at University of Indonesia

May 2016 - Present

Origin Business Club, an initiative by the Management Student Society (MSS) Faculty of Business and Economics of Universitas Indonesia, is looking for mentors/speakers who love to share their experience and knowledge to breed young Indonesian entrepreneurs.

#### **Guest Lecture at BINUS International School**

October 2015 - Present

Guest lecture at BINUS International "Incubators and Funding: Enabler and User for "International Entrepreneurship" course

#### Guest Lecture at Atma Jaya Catholic University

May 2015 - Present

Program Studi Manajemen Fakultas Ekonomi akan mengadakan Pameran dan Talkshow yang bertemakan: "Industri Kreatif sebagai Masa Depan Perekonomian Indonesia".

#### Radio broadcaster at Satu Indonesia Radio (www.satuindonesia.co.nz)

November 2005 - February 2012

Volunteer community Radio host (November 05 – February 12)

#### MC for Indonesian GIST Bootcamp and Demo day at CRDF Global

April 2014 - Present

The GIST Startup Boot Camp is designed for high potential tech entrepreneurs from idea stage to 5 years in operation who are ready and committed to launch new business endeavors. The ventures should be in the areas of ICT, Agriculture, Energy and Healthcare. - See more at:

http://gist.crdfglobal.org/gist-programs/gist-startup-boot-camp

Languages

English Indonesian (Full professional proficiency)

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

**Telecommunications** 

**Technical Support** 

**Troubleshooting** 

**Customer Service** 

**Technical Analysis** 

**Sales** 

Leadership

Wireless

**Public Speaking** 

**Call Centers** 

**Customer Support** 

**Customer Experience** 

**Analysis** 

**Fault Management** 

**Analytical Skills** 

**Start-ups** 

**Service Improvement** 

**Time Management** 

**ADSL** 

**Service Delivery** 

Retail

**Volunteering** 

**Fundraising** 

Refugees

**Team Leadership** 

**Team Building** 

**Personal Development** 

**Personal Training** 

E-commerce

**Sports** 

**Digital Marketing** 

Merchandising

## Education

#### **Massey University**

Bachelor of Information System Science, Information Science/Studies, 2006 - 2008

#### **University of Wollongong**

Diploma of Information of Technology, Information Technology, 2005 - 2006

#### Al-Azhar Kemang Pratama High School

#### **Interests**

Technology, Startup, Digital Solution, Entrepreneurship, Event, Telecommunication, Football, DJ, Music, Travelling, Sports, Health & Fitness

# Rama Dhonanto

Co-founder at Sportdeca.com

ramapost2000@yahoo.com



# 1 person has recommended Rama

"Rama is a hugely intelligent and energetic young guy, with a passion not just for achieving, but for doing so in the "right" way. He works hard and has a huge desire to succeed, but all his decisions are based out of a moral compass that never wavers. During my time working with Rama I found him to be a diligent and skilled analyst, which he complimented well with his major contribution to the team culture. I would not hesitate in recommending Rama to any prospective employer or client"

— Nick Jensen, managed Rama at Chorus

Contact Rama on LinkedIn